cosmosmagazine.com 2018-12-21

# Privacy Policy | Cosmos

The Royal Institution of Australia Inc (referred to as "RiAus" or "We" hereafter") recognises the importance of your privacy and we are committed to protecting your personal information.

This privacy policy covers all personal information that we hold.

**SECTION 1 - WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION?**

When you purchase something from RiAus, as part of the buying and selling process, we collect the personal information you give us such as your name, address and email address. We also automatically receive your computer’s internet protocol (IP) address in order to provide us with information that helps us learn about your browser and operating system.

We will not combine information collected from your browser or device with personal information you have submitted without your prior consent. We only use this information for statistical and internal purposes including improving the functionality of RiAus' websites or mobile apps for our users.

Only authorised and audited RiAus staff can view your personal information once we receive it.  

From time to time, RiAus will invite you to participate in surveys. These surveys are designed to ensure that our products and services remain as relevant to you as possible. RiAus will always advise if the survey is anonymous or if your participation will be linked to you in any way.

Subscribers may choose to be removed from RiAus email lists at any time by changing communication preferences in their account settings.

RiAus will use personal information provided to it for our primary purposes and secondary purposes. By agreeing to this policy, you consent to RiAus using your personal information for the following:

 _ **Primary purposes**_

  * Providing you with products and services you have ordered, or contacting you in relation to these orders
  * Answering direct enquiries
  * Informing you of new products which may be of interest to you
  * Providing customer service
  * Complying with legal obligations where necessary
  * Allowing us to run our business and perform administrative and operational tasks, such as:  
training staff;  
developing and marketing products and services;  
risk management;  
systems development and testing, including our websites and other online channels;  
undertaking planning, research and statistical analysis;

 _ **Secondary purposes**_

  * Billing and account management
  * Improving our products, services and websites
  * Improving our marketing and promotional efforts
  * Improving the accuracy of the personal information we hold

We may also use your personal information to get a better understanding of your needs. Unless you tell us otherwise, we may use this information to bring you products and services which we believe will benefit you. Upon receiving new products and services for the first time, you will be given the option to opt-in immediately to receive future offerings of the item in question.  

 **SECTION 2 - CONSENT**  

**How do you get my consent?**

When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order, arrange for a delivery or return a purchase, we imply that you consent to our collecting it and using it for that specific reason only.

If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason, like marketing, we will either ask you directly for your expressed consent, or provide you with an opportunity to say no.

If this privacy policy changes in future in response to changes in legislation, you may be asked to re-consent to your personal details being held.

**How do I withdraw my consent?**

If after you opt-in, you change your mind, you may withdraw your consent for us to contact you, for the continued collection, use or disclosure of your information, at anytime, by contacting us by one of the methods listed at the end of this Privacy Policy.

RiAus takes reasonable precautions to ensure that the personal information we collect and use is complete, relevant and up-to-date. However, the accuracy of the personal information we receive depends to a large extent on the information you provide. We recommend you let us know if there are any errors in your personal information by contacting RiAus.  

**SECTION 3 - DISCLOSURE**

Personal information will not be used for any other purpose without the consent of its provider unless RiAus is required by law to disclose that information, or if you violate our terms of service. RiAus may be required to disclose personal information to third parties in order to provide a service that you requested.

Other than in circumstances such as these, RiAus will not disclose personal information provided, such as name, address, email address or telephone number, to any organisation or person outside RiAus unless the provider has clearly and directly authorised RiAus to do so.  

**SECTION 4 - PAYMENT**

Payment is completed using Stripe, then Chargebee stores your credit card data and Xero stores transaction records. It is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is stored only as long as is necessary to complete your purchase transaction.

All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover.

PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of credit card information.

 **SECTION 5 - EMAIL DELIVERY**

Our newsletters are administered through Mailchimp - this means some of your information is stored on a Mailchimp server. This includes your email address, IP address and certain information about the links you click within the emails we send you. Mailchimp will never share your personal information with any other party, unless they are legally compelled to do so, and will only contact you if you initiate contact with them first. Only authorised Mailchimp employees have access to our subscriber list.  

**SECTION 6 - THIRD-PARTY SERVICES**

In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us.

However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.

For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers. Their respective privacy policies are listed below:

In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.

As an example, if you are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the United States, then your personal information used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.

Once you leave our store’s website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s Terms of Service.

**Links:**

When you click on links on our online store, they may direct you away from our site. This in no way constitutes an endorsement of those sites or their content and RiAus has no control over the conduct of the companies or organisations operating those sites. Before you disclose any personal information to such a site, we advise you to check its terms and conditions, including its privacy and security policies.

**SECTION 7 - SECURITY**

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed. We encourage you to play an important role in keeping your personal information secure, by maintaining the confidentiality of any passwords and account details used on our websites. It is your sole responsibility to maintain such confidentiality and RiAus will not be liable for any damage, loss or expense suffered due to such disclosure.

If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

**SECTION 8 - COOKIES**

RiAus uses cookies to manage user access and subscriptions. A cookie is a small text file that a server places on your hard drive to identify that subsequent requests to a site have come from the same user. RiAus uses cookies to ‘remember’ your browser between page visits.

Cookies are pieces of information that a website can transfer to an individual’s computer hard drive for tracking user navigation and customising site information to further improve the user experience. Cookies can make using RiAus’ website easier, for example by storing information about your preferences on a particular website. The use of cookies is an industry standard and you’ll find most major websites use them.  

Here is a list of cookies that we use. We’ve listed them here so you that you can choose if you want to opt-out of cookies or not.

**_ga _gat _gid** – Google Analytics data

 **_parsely_visitor _parsely_session** – Parse.ly analytic data  

**_viewed _articles** – articles on the website that have been viewed

 **_stripe_mid _stripe_sid** – Stripe payments data

 **_cosmos_session _remember_susbcriber_token** \- internal cookies for remembering users and sessions

RiAus uses Google Analytics and Parse.ly. Google and Parse.ly, as third-party vendors, use cookies to serve ads on this site.

Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our sites and other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads). For more details on the kind of information collected by Google click [here](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/1348695?ctx=as2&hl=en-GB&rd=1).

The Parse.ly privacy policy can be visited [here](https://www.parse.ly/privacy-policy/).

**SECTION 9 - AGE OF CONSENT**

By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this site. You will be asked to confirm your age or parental consent when submitting any personal details through the Cosmos Magazine website.

 **SECTION 10 - CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**  

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

If our online store is acquired or merged with another company, your information may be transferred to the new owners so that we may continue to sell products to you.

**SECTION 11 - ACCESSING YOUR INFORMATION** **  
**

You can request the personal information we hold about you by contacting us by one of the methods listed at the end of this Privacy Policy. There is no fee for making such requests and we will endeavour to make your information available within 28 days of the initial request. RiAus reserves the right to confirm your identity before providing you with this information.

RiAus takes reasonable precautions to ensure that the personal information we collect and use is complete, relevant and up-to-date. However, the accuracy of the personal information we receive depends to a large extent on the information you provide. We recommend you let us know if there are any errors in your personal information by contacting RiAus.

 **SECTION 12 - MAKING A COMPLAINT**

If you have a concern about your privacy, you have a right to make a complaint and we’ll do everything we can to put matters right.

To lodge a complaint, please get in touch with us using the contact details provided below. RiAus will review your complaint and endeavour to resolve it immediately.

We acknowledge every complaint we receive and provide contact details of the investigating officer. We keep you updated on the progress we’re making towards resolving your issue.

Usually, it takes only a few days to resolve a complaint. However, if we’re unable to provide a final response within 30 days, we’ll contact you to explain why and discuss a timeframe to resolve the complaint.

 **SECTION 13 - CONTACTING US**

If you would like to: access, correct, amend or delete any personal information we have about you, register a complaint, or simply want more information contact our Privacy Compliance Officer at subscribe@cosmosmagazine.com or by mail at:

**Privacy Officer**  
 **The Royal Institution of Australia Inc**  
 **55 Exchange Place  
** **Adelaide SA 5000  
Australia**

 **Phone +61 8 7120** **  
Email[subscribe@cosmosmagazine.com](mailto:subscribe@cosmosmagazine.com)**
